

PROFILE

My objective in life is to have a job that wants me to get up in the morning happy to start a job in hand. For many years this has been the case, but we can't control everything, so sometimes we must accept less. I'm looking for something new, something that excites me again.

I wish to settle in Barcelona area, so I'm look for work that will help me towards that goal. I'm currently based in Paris. As I am currently employed, I would need to honour a notice period of a minimum of a month.

CONTACT

PHONE: 00 33 6 24 13 15 24 00 34 682 75 59 46

LINKEDIN: www.linkedin.com/in/j.mclaughin

EMAIL:

<u>ferranclosa@gmail.com</u> or <u>ferran.closa@hsbc.fr</u>

WFB:

https://ferranclosa.eu

ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

Muisic (both listen and playing)
Being a father
Travelling
Cinema
Reading
Going out with Friends

FERRAN CLOSA CERVERA

IT Enterprise Architect

EXPERIENCE

IT Commercial BANKING Architect •HSBC Continental EUROPE – 08/2008 – now

Following an organisational alignment between Domains and Business lines, and in view that Migrations were no longer necessary at big scale, I moved to Commercial Banking, where I took a Solution Architect position, working on the implementation of Group (HSBC) systems into the fold of the French infrastructure.

A big programme, called IT Modernisation, was initiated and I did get involved, specially working on the implementation of a set of Microservices, which took me to a path of the new technologies, like Cloud, DevOps, SpringBoot, Java, Mulesoft etc. I took several in-house training courses and soon, I found myself implementing what I had learn and took on the training of our team, to bring them up to speed.

Another project I got involved with was a Business Internet Banking replacement from a legacy CGI based to a React + API system. This is still ongoing, but I was the one that got first trained on React so that I could train and help the development team in charge of the application.

RESPONSABLE de DOMAIN (Migration) • HSBC France • 08/2002 – 07/2008

I oversaw all data migration projects related to the HSBC arrival in the French market, following its acquisition of the CCF group. This Group consisted of 9 smaller banks, which had to be 'migrated' to HSBC systems, respecting the natural risk management appetite by the business

Between 8 and 20 people depending on project at hand.

My main goals during this time were concentrated around Reconciliation (Accounting and Migration), Performance, Validation and Testing. Using either the source (usually COBOL, or C) ort the target (usually RPGLE, or Java). We perfected the ETL model, creating a whole framework that has been exported to other HSBC countries as the recommended approach for Core Banking Migrations.

SENIOR DEVLOPER (Migration LEAD) • HSBC UK • 03/1998 - 07/2002

During this period, I was on the European Support Branch of HSBC Systems

My responsibilities included offering support to all European HSBC sites, with their IT Infrastructure, Upgrade planning, Installation of new Installations. I was responsible for the implementation of the IT infrastructure for three countries (Belgique, Ireland and Luxembourg) where HSBC started operations.

It just happened that during this time there was a few HSBC acquisitions that required migration from the 'old' to the HSBC systems, and I slowly took that role where they just sent me as Migration Lead. Malta; Athens, Istanbul, Madrid, Bermuda, Vancouver, where some of the destinations I was sent to. And then, France.

HEAD of DISTANCE LEARNING • FORBES UK • 08/1995 - 03/1998

Having created the Distance Learning systems at Forbes they put me in charge overseeing the operation, which was a new market at the time.

My responsibility was the creation and adaptation of courses for this new medium. Also, in the automation of predictable flow processes, like Test marking, customer enrolment, notifications, etc.

TRAINER • FORBES UK • 08/1994 - 03/1998

This was a very fulfilling part of my professional career. I just loved teaching programming. Although I have moved on to other roles, one that I do at heart is this one. I love learning, and I love teaching and making sure that I make a difference.

I taught iSeries, RPG, COBOL, Visual Basic and ObjectPascal (Delphi). These were also the tools I used to build the Distance Learning module that would later be adopted by the company. It all started as a pet project, put together to show to students, how we could make a difference.

VIOLINIST- VIOLIN TEACHER 08/1983 - 01/1992

I was professional violinist in different orchestras in Spain, as well as violin teacher on different Conservatories in Spain.

EDUCATION

MUSIC & VIOLIN Profesor • 06/1981 • Conservatorio Municipal de Música, BARCELONA

This was my childhood vocation

COBOL, RPG, MQ, Java etc

During my career, I have many attended courses as part of my ongoing training within the company. All based of the 'need to know' basis.

TEAM LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

As ETL expert, for around 12 years I oversaw a team with ETL responsibilities across the whole organisation. The team was made up of between 8 and 20 colleagues. Something I'm proud off is that, after all these years, we still meet on a regular basis to catch up on each other and we have remained friends.